Borns Jewish Studies Program records, 1972-2010 C407
Indiana University Archives
Borns Jewish Studies Program records
1972-2010
Indiana University Archives
Robert A. and Sandra S. Borns Jewish Studies Program (Indiana University, Bloomington)
C407
13 cubic feet
The Robert. A. and Sandra S. Borns Jewish Studies Program was established on the Bloomington campus in 1972 with the aid of a Lilly Endowment. It is now one of the largest and oldest programs supporting the interdisciplinary study of the Jewish people and civilization. The collection consists of the program's administrative and subject files documenting the creation and growth of the program and includes correspondence, reports, newsletters, videos, and photographic material.
Access Restrictions
Select files are closed to researchers. These are indicated in the finding aid. Advance notice required for access.
Administrative History
In 1972, the Indiana University Jewish Studies program began with a single Jewish literature class taught by English professor Alvin H. Rosenfeld to indulge his own academic interests and the growing interest of the student body. During the 1972-1973 academic year, the program saw its official beginnings, with help from a grant from the Lilly Endowment, and in 1992 the program was renamed the Robert A. and Sandra S. Borns Jewish Studies program. Today the program, is known as one of the country's leading centers on Jewish research with an interdisciplinary program including faculty in anthropology, history, literature, linguistics, philosophy, political science, religious studies, and others.
Expanding form meager beginnings, in 1976 the program began offering a certificate in Jewish Studies and in 1992 a Bachelor of Arts degree. Today the program offers a Master of Arts in Jewish Studies and a PhD minor. Each year the program hosts numerous distinguished lectures, film screenings, Hebrew conversation hours, and social gatherings often in coordination with the Helene G. Simon Hillel Center on the Bloomington campus.
Arrangement
Collection is organized into five series: Administrative files, Correspondence, Publications, Subject files, and Multimedia.
Scope and Content Note
The Borns Jewish Studies Program records span the period from the Program's beginning in 1972 through 2010. The collection is organized into five series: Administrative files, Correspondence, Publications, Subject files, and Multimedia.
The Administrative files series (1974-2007) includes materials relating to the faculty and staff of the Jewish Studies program such as information about committees, events, and research. Other files relate to the program in general, such as the bachelor's degree and certificate requirements, lectures, files on Tal Bet Shemesh (a summer archaeological program in Israel), and the Piser essay prize.
The Correspondence series (1975-2008) includes interdepartmental communication and emails from the program faculty and administrators to all students in the program regarding upcoming events and opportunities.
The Publications series includes both newsletters and newsletter preparation materials from 1983-2010.
The Subject files series is arranged alphabetically by folder title and includes materials on Judaism and Jewish Studies, Israel, and Indiana University. It ranges from 1972-2000. Some topics of interest include the Indiana Sukkot Project and the Jewish Book Council.
The Multimedia series contains videocassette recordings of the Jewish Studies Program's sponsored lectures. Included in this series recordings from the Portrait of a People Series and Connections: The Jewish Experience in History, Thought, and Music Series. Dates range from 1978-1984.
Separated Material
Six issues of AJS Review journal in library collection were removed.
Six WTIU films were pulled and filed with other WTIU films in the Archives collection:
Indiana University Television Q472
Series: Major Epochs in Jewish History
Fischel #1-Rise of the Sages
Record Date 2/1/77
Indiana University Television Q1140
Series: Portrait of a People
PGM. 11: American Jewish Writing, 2
Record Date 11/21/78
Indiana University Television Q776
Series: Major Epochs in Jewish History
Remembering the Holocaust-Rosenfeld
Record Date 4/77
Indiana University Television Q1073
Series: Portrait of a People
PGM. 9: Lit. of the Holocaust
Record Date 11/06/78
Indiana University Television Q972
Series: Connections
The Musical Spirit of a People: The Art of the Cantor
Record Date 5/7/80
Indiana University Television Q272
Series: Major Epochs in Jewish History
Fischel #2- Development of the Midrash
Record Date 2/19/77
Photographs Pulled
Approximately 2 boxes of photos, contact sheets, eight negatives were removed and transferred to the photograph collection. Photographic materials documented student events, lectures, and receptions, and were used in newsletters and newsletter preparation materials.
Related Material
Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory
Acquisition Information
Accession Information: 2010/077, 2011/030, 2011/011
Provenance
Transferred from the Indiana University Jewish Studies Program to the University Archives, Aug. 2010.
Jews --Study and teaching --Indiana --Bloomington.; Indiana University, Bloomington. Jewish Studies Program; Indiana University, Bloomington. Jewish Studies Program -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. Jewish Studies Program -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University, Bloomington. Jewish Studies Program -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Robert A. and Sandra S. Borns Jewish Studies Program (Indiana University, Bloomington) -- Archives; Robert A. and Sandra S. Borns Jewish Studies Program (Indiana University, Bloomington) -- Records and correspondence; Robert A. and Sandra S. Borns Jewish Studies Program (Indiana University, Bloomington) -- History -- Sources
- Administrative files, 1974-2007; undated (Box 1)
  - Advising at Hebrew University in Jerusalem (HUJ), 2000 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, Jewish Studies Program, 1974-1986 (Box 1)
  - Bachelors Degree, 1992-2001; undated (Box 1)
    - Articles about new B.A. degree, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Worksheets, undated (Box 1)
    - Requirement sheet, undated (Box 1)
    - Contract, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - Flyer, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - First B.A./faculty gathering, 1993 (Box 1)
      General
      (Restricted materials removed)
    - Average Major GPA, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Flyer, undated (Box 1)
    - Requirement forms, undated (Box 1)
    - Worksheets, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Contract, undated (Box 1)
    - Changing major requirements, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
    - New major requirements contract, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Worksheets, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    - Requirements, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    - Flyer, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    - Contract, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    - List of JS students given to faculty on, 8 November 2001 (Box 1)
      (Restricted)
  - Background Checks, "Hire Right", 2004-2005 (Box 1)
  - Bulletins, 1993-2004 (Box 1)
    - Jewish Studies Program Bulletin, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Changes for copy of 1994 Jewish Studies Program Bulletin, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - Jewish Studies blurb in University Planner, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - College Of Arts and Sciences Bulletin, 1994 (Box 1)
    - College Of Arts and Sciences Bulletin, 1996-1998 (Box 1)
    - Bulletin changes, 1998-2000 (Box 1)
    - Bulletin copy/student form changes, 1998-2000 (Box 1)
    - Bulletin copy, 2002-2004 (Box 1)
  - Certificate, 1975-1999; undated (Box 1)
    - General information, undated (Box 1)
    - Flyer, undated (Box 1)
    - Change in certificate requirements, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Student information sheets, undated (Box 1)
    - Requirement sheets, undated (Box 1)
    - Contract, undated (Box 1)
    - Application for certificate, new program, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Certificate program public lecture and reception, 1976 (Box 1)
    - IUCARE Certificate list of students, 1994-1999 (Box 1)
    - Certificate completion letter, 1986-1992 (Box 1)
    - Flyer, undated (Box 1)
    - Requirement sheets, undated (Box 1)
    - Worksheets (student information sheets), 1994 (Box 1)
    - Certificate contract, undated (Box 1)
  - Committees, 2002-2003 (Box 1)
  - Committee Assignments, 1993-2007 (Box 1)
  - Courses, 1975-2003; undated (Box 1)
    - Course correspondence, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Overseas study, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Jewish Studies courses and course descriptions, Fall 1993 (Box 1)
    - Requests for course descriptions, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Problem covering R245, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Course enrollment figures, 1994-2003 (Box 1)
    - Course descriptions, Spring 1996 (Box 1)
    - Jewish Studies courses, 1997-2003 (Box 1)
    - Faculty course evaluations, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Information for course description booklet, undated (Box 1)
  - Departmentalization proposal, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Distribution requirement sheets, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
    - Students starting before Summer 1994, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Students beginning Summer 1994, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Students beginning Summer 1996 (Box 1)
    - Distribution charts, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Events, 1978-2003; undated (Box 1)
    - Updates for faculty, 1988-2000 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Dinner, August 1993 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Retreat, December 1993 (Box 1)
    - Party Ideas, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Dinner, Fall 1995 (Box 1)
    - Schedule of events (Box 1)
      - 1996-1997 (Box 1)
      - Spring 1997 (Box 1)
      - Spring-Summer 1997 (Box 1)
    - Edgar Bronfman, 1997; undated (Box 1)
    - "Germany and the Jews" JS Faculty Workshop, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Welcome Event, Fall 2002 (Box 1)
    - Faculty meeting, Spring 2003 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Retreat, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Gala in Honor of Alvin Rosenfeld, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
    - Mini Retreat, Summer 2003 (Box 1)
    - Jewish Studies Alumni Retreat, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Hiring (Box 1)
    - General faculty search materials for Affirmative Action, 1984-2005 (Box 1)
    - Pat M. Glazer Chair, 2nd Year of the Search, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    - Pat M. Glazer Visiting Position, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    - Schottenstein Visiting Position, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Faculty phone and address list organization, undated (Box 1)
  - Faculty Summary Report, 1982-1987 (Box 1)
  - Foreign Culture Implementation, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Fellowship, 1994-1999 (Box 1)
    - 1994 (Box 1)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 1)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - High School Honors Day, 1980-1986 (Box 1)
  - History Department handbook, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Honors Program, undated (Box 2)
    - Flyer, undated (Box 2)
    - Procedures Forms, undated (Box 2)
  - Human Resources- Personnel Representatives Notes, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - Indiana University Press, 1992-2002 (Box 2)
    - Finder's Fees, 1989-2001 (Box 2)
    - Jewish Studies Titles, 1989-2002 (Box 2)
    - General (Box 2)
      - 1992 (Box 2)
      - 1993 (Box 2)
      - 1994 (Box 2)
      - 1995 (Box 2)
      - 1996 (Box 2)
      - 1997 (Box 2)
      - 1998 (Box 2)
      - 1999 (Box 2)
      - 2000 (Box 2)
    - IU Press Dinner, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
    - Gary Weissman, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Jewish Studies Program, 1979; 1983; undated (Box 2)
    - Flyers, undated (Box 2)
    - History, undated (Box 2)
    - Logo copyright, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Questionnaire, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Leaves, Retirement, and Sabbaticals, 1997-2001 (Box 2)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 2)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 2)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - Lectures, 1991-2001 (Box 2)
    - Co-sponsored lectures, 1991-1995 (Box 2)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 2)
      - 1992-1993 (Box 2)
      - 1993-1994 (Box 2)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 2)
      - 1995-1996 (Box 2)
    - Comprehensive lecture list, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Lectures Committee, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
      - Spring 2000 (Box 2)
      - Fall 2000 (Box 2)
      - Fall 2001 (Box 2)
    - Suggestions for 2007-2008 Lectures, 2005-2006 (Box 2)
  - Library Information, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Library Acquisitions, 1988-1994 (Box 2)
  - Office Materials, 1998-2007; undated (Box 2)
  - Office Structure, 1998-2000 (Box 2)
  - Piser Essay Prize, 1983-1989 (Box 2)
    - 1983 (Box 2)
      (Redacted for privacy)
    - 1984 (Box 2)
    - 1985 (Box 2)
    - 1986 (Box 2)
    - 1987 (Box 2)
    - 1988 (Box 2)
    - 1989 (Box 2)
  - Recruitment, 1979-1992 (Box 2)
  - Registration, 1994; 1997 (Box 2)
    - Admission tickets, 1994 (Box 2)
    - General, Fall 1997 (Box 2)
  - Research, 1993-2003 (Box 2)
    - Bonus research funds, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Faculty research funds, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Research Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
    - Research support for faculty, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Research Proposals for Special Grants (Box 2)
    - Deadline: December 2, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Deadline: January 28, 2005, 2004-2006 (Box 2)
  - Responsibilities of tenured faculty, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Scholarships, 1982; 2006 (Box 2)
    - Isaac and Miriam Schwartz Scholarship Fund, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Wisen Scholarships, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Tel Bet Shemesh, 1994-2007; undated (Box 2)
    - Original organization, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
    - Handbook and basic materials, 1995-1997 (Box 2)
    - General, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Hebrew University in Jerusalem (HUJ) students, 1995 (Box 2)
    - International Activities Report, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
    - Funding, 1995-1999 (Box 2)
    - Student totals, 1996-2001 (Box 2)
    - Participants, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Publicity, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Scholarships, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Sister city hosting, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Funding for summers, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Handbook, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Summer 1997 (Box 2)
    - Scholarships, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
    - Handbook and participants, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Report, 1998 (Box 2)
    - ideas, Summer 1998 (Box 2)
    - Brochure ordering, 1999 (Box 2)
    - General, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Summer 1999 (Box 2)
    - Support for Tal Bet Shemesh, 1999 (Box 2)
    - General, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Listing of credits, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Participants, Summer 2000 (Box 2)
    - Recruitment, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Summary, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Summer 2000 (Box 2)
    - General, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Cancellation, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Dorot Travel Grant for Tel Bet Shemesh, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Summer 2002 (Box 2)
    - Summer workshop, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Raising Question of Tal Beth Shemesh, 2003 (Box 2)
    - General, 2003-2005 (Box 2)
    - Past Tal Bet Shemesh support, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Summer 2006 (Box 2)
    - Cancellation, Summer 2007 (Box 2)
    - Tel Bet Shemesh release form, undated (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1975-2008 (Box 2)
  - Course Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Institute for Advanced Studies, 1982-1994 (Box 2)
  - History Department Notes and Correspondence, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Letter to Faculty about Overseas Study, 1989 (Box 2)
    (moved)
  - Correspondence Re: Shofar Journal, 1991-1998 (Box 3)
  - Holocaust Education Foundation Academic Advisory Board, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Kenneth Gros Louis, 1992; 2001 (Box 3)
  - Earlham College, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Myles Brand, 1994-2003 (Box 3)
  - Rosenfeld, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Symposium on Polish-Jewish Relations, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Gloria Gibson, 1995 (Box 3)
  - International Programs Mentoring Program, 1995 (Box 3)
  - William Kolbrener, 1995 (Box 3)
  - School of Continuing Studies, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Comments about Jewish Studies, 1996-2001 (Box 3)
  - Electronic Lists Messages, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Electronic List File, 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Newsletter Responses, 1996-2001 (Box 3)
  - New Years Cards, 1997; 2001; undated (Box 3)
  - Anti-Semitic/Hate Mail, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Bak Exhibition, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Emails, 2000-2008 (Box 3)
    - Students, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
    - Summer mailings, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Requests to faculty, Fall 2001 (Box 3)
    - Students, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
    - Seniors, April 2002 (Box 3)
    - Summer mailings, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Faculty, Fall 2002 (Box 3)
    - Weekly email lists, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
    - Students, Fall 2003 (Box 3)
    - Freshman, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Students, 2003-2004 (Box 3)
    - Freshman, Fall 2004 (Box 3)
    - General (Box 3)
      - Fall 2004 (Box 3)
      - Spring 2005 (Box 3)
      - Fall 2005 (Box 3)
      - Spring 2006 (Box 3)
    - Students, Fall 2006 (Box 3)
    - General, 2007 (Box 3)
      - Summer 2007 (Box 3)
      - Spring 2007 (Box 3)
    - First emails, Fall 2007 (Box 3)
    - General (Box 3)
      - Fall 2007 (Box 3)
      - Spring 2008 (Box 3)
  - Sharon Brehm, 2001-2003 (Box 3)
  - Gwyn Richards, School of Music, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Yoav Gelber, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Olga Borovaya, Fulbright Visiting Scholar, 2003-2004 (Box 3)
  - Adam W. Herbert, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence with Spectrum Press, 2004 (Box 3)
- Publications, 1983-2010; undated (Box 3)
  - Friends of Jewish Studies, 1995; 1997 (Box 3)
    - Newsletters and preparation materials (Box 3)
      - 1995 (Box 3)
      - 1997 (Box 3)
  - In Honor of Robert A. Borns on the Occasion of His 75th Birthday, 2010 (Box 3)
  - Indiana University Foundation Publication Survey, undated (Box 3)
  - Lecture Programs, 1983-2002 (Box 3)
  - Jewish Studies Notes preparation materials, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Jewish Studies Program Newsletter, 1983-2008; undated (Box 4)
    - Newsletter preparation materials, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter correspondence, 1984-1997 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter preparation materials (Box 4)
      - 1984 (Box 4)
      - 1986 (Box 4)
        (photos transferred to photograph collection)
    - Newsletter and newsletter preparation materials (Box 4)
      - 1982-1986 (Box 4)
      - 1987 (Box 4)
      - 1988 (Box 4)
      - 1989 (Box 4)
      - 1990 (Box 4)
      - 1991 (Box 4)
      - 1992 (Box 4)
      - 1993 (Box 4)
    - Profiles for newsletter, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
    - Alumni Association support of newsletters, 1994 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter and preparation materials, 1994 (Box 4)
    - Newsletters, 1995 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter preparation materials with, 1995 (Box 4)
      (photo negatives transferred to photograph collection)
    - Estimates for Jewish Studies Newsletter, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter preparation materials, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Newsletters, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Estimates for Jewish Studies Newsletter, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Newsletters and preparation materials, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Newsletters, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter copyright information, 1998-2000 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter preparation materials, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter printing, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter redesign, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Newsletters and preparation materials, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Photos for future newsletters, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter preparation and production, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Mailing lists, 2001-2004 (Box 4)
    - Permission to print artwork from British Library, 2001-2003 (Box 4)
    - Rights to print artwork, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter printing and production, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Newsletter artwork permission, 2002-2003 (Box 5)
    - Estimates for Jewish Studies Newsletter, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter mailing list additions, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter preparation materials, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Newsletters and preparation materials, 2002 (Box 5)
      (includes 2 CDs and Zip Disk)
    - Estimates for newsletters, 2003-2007 (Box 5)
    - Alumni periodicals policies, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter correspondence, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Permission to use photography forms, 2003-2004 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter PDF file, 2003 (Box 5)
      (includes Zip Disk)
    - Newsletters and preparation materials, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter, Alumni News draft, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter, Correspondence with Rabinowitch, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter, S. Weitzman's Column, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter preparation materials, 2004 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter preparation materials, 2005 (Box 5)
    - Newsletters and preparation materials, 2006 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter preparation materials, 2007; (3 folders) (Box 5)
    - Newsletters and preparation materials, 2008; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Art books and newsletter, undated (Box 5)
    - Negatives of artwork used, undated (Box 5)
      (negatives transferred to photograph collection)
    - Printing information, undated (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Jewish Studies Program Publications, 1978-2009 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Publications used for teaching, 1987-1997 (Box 5)
- Subject files, 1972-2009; undated (Box 5)
  - Ads in Journals/Newspapers, 2000-2007 (Box 5)
  - The American Israel Public Affairs Committee (AIPAC), 1988 (Box 5)
  - Arts Committee, 1998-2002 (Box 5)
  - Association for Jewish Studies, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Atran Foundation, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Bar-Ilan University invitation to Holocaust Memorial Day, 2009 (Box 5)
  - "Bernstei.txt" in Word Perfect for Windows Ver. 6.0a & DOS 6.2, undated; (Floppy Disk) (Box 5)
  - Bitburg in Moral and Political Perspective. Edited by Geoffrey Hartman, 1985-1987 (Box 5)
  - Bitburg lecture for McGill and Oberlin, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Book/MS Reviews by Alvin H. Rosenberg, 1990-1994 (Box 5)
  - Circles of Community conference, 1996 (Box 5)
  - College of Arts and Sciences Endowment Campaign, 1994-2000 (Box 5)
  - College of Arts and Sciences Materials, 1989-2005 (Box 5)
    (primarily correspondence)
  - The Covenant Program, 1990-1993 (Box 5)
  - Did the Holocaust Happen?, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Directory of publishers, undated (Box 5)
  - Economic forecasts for universities, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
    (clippings)
  - Face-to-Face, ADL Publication, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary of the State of Israel, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Holocaust and Genocide Studies, 1986; 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - General Assembly, November 1997 (Box 5)
  - German media lists, from Benn's Media Directory, 1992 (Box 5)
  - The Goldsmith-Greenfield Foundation, 1996-1998 (Box 5)
  - Holocaust information, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Holocaust Publications, Inc. (Alexander Donat Resource Center), 1984 (Box 5)
  - Indiana Sukkot Project, 1995-1997; undated (Box 5)
    - undated (Box 5)
    - 1995-1997 (Box 5)
  - Iranian Jews, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Israel Arts and Sciences Academy, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Israel Conference, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Israeli-PLO Pact, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Jerusalem hotels, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Jerusalem map, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Jewish Book Council, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Jewish-Christian relations, 1981-1984 (Box 6)
  - Jewish Studies as a field, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Jewish Studies Job Vacancies, 2000-2002 (Box 6)
  - Jewish Studies Program, 1984-1989 (Box 6)
    - IUPUI, 1984-1987 (Box 6)
    - Purdue, 1984-1989 (Box 6)
  - Jewish United Fund, Chicago, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Judaica ListServ, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Kibbutz Langdon Grant Application, 1988 (Box 6)
  - L'Arche article and translation, American Paradoxes by Pierre Birnbaum, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Logo copyright for Come and Learn, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Mailing Lists (Box 6)
    - 1986, 1992-1997 (Box 6)
    - 1989-2003, (invoices, floppy disk) (Box 6)
  - Middle Eastern Center, 1981-1983 (Box 6)
  - Midwest Jewish Studies Association, 1990-1993 (Box 6)
  - Newspaper articles, 1989-1997 (Box 6)
  - Poland, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Polish-Jewish relations, 1981-1986 (Box 6)
  - Popularization and Memory: the Case of Anne Frank, 1989; 1991 (Box 6)
  - Reviews and Synopses of Books re: Jewish-Christian relations, 1980-1981 (Box 6)
  - Risk Management Newsletters, 1995 (Box 6)
  - Rockefeller Grant Application, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Ruth N. Halls Chair, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
  - Sephardic Studies, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Sh'ma- A publication of Jewish Family & Life, undated (Box 6)
  - Shofar, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Soviet Refuseniks, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Strategic Directives Charter, 1995-1997 (Box 6)
    - 1995 (Box 6)
    - 1996, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 1997 (Box 6)
  - Substitute Terminology, 1976; 1980 (Box 6)
  - Synagogue Directory, undated (Box 6)
  - Testament to Courage, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Thinking about the Holocaust: After Fifty Years Rosenfeld, 1996 (Box 6)